[{"id": "58c9f7f3b4e2c7fbd389674e", "question": "What year was Strongbow cider introduced to the market?", "answer": "1962", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a25d", "question": "Which famous rapper was born Stanley Kirk Burrel in 1962?", "answer": "MC Hammer", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a46b", "question": "What is the most northern capital city in Europe?", "answer": "Reyjkavik", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5fd", "question": "What US city is known as the \"City of Brotherly Love\"?", "answer": "Philadelphia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5ee", "question": "Which river forms part of the border between England & Scotland?", "answer": "River Tweed", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fb083c6cf631c2414a13b48", "question": "What is meteorology the study of?", "answer": "Weather Forecasting", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e7", "question": "What is the longest one syllable word in the English language?", "answer": "Screeched", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5921fe82a4edfd43a087adcf", "question": "What does a ventriloquist typically hold on their lap?", "answer": "A puppet", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a30a", "question": "What character did Natascha McElhone play on the TV show \"Californication\"?", "answer": "Karen", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b519", "question": "What religious day follows Halloween?", "answer": "All Saint's Day", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe7ccf3877e98cb97778a2f", "question": "What British island, accessible by road only at low tide, is also known as Holy Island?", "answer": "Lindisfarne", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe7c6ae877e98cb977789be", "question": "Which small French town holds an annual festival celebrating Mexico?", "answer": "Barcelonnette", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338de1", "question": "From what language did English borrow the word \"zero\"?", "answer": "Arabic", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d4a", "question": "In 1803 The Louvre was renamed to what?", "answer": "Mus\u00e9e Napol\u00e9on", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bce7", "question": "What French company is represented by a mascot named \"Bibendum\"?", "answer": "Michelin", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133969a", "question": "The 1975 movie \"The Man Who Would Be King\" is based on the tales of which author?", "answer": "Rudyard Kipling", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acc0", "question": "What is the \"Big Mac\" that was built in Michigan in 1957?", "answer": "The Mackinac Bridge", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393ea", "question": "The music band \"The Cardigans\" hail from what European country?", "answer": "Sweden", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "601b4c9b49076251badbead8", "question": "Who was the first American to orbit the Earth?", "answer": "John Glenn -- He orbited the Earth three times in five hours in a Mercury space capsule he named \"Friendship 7\".", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b439", "question": "What year was Albert Einstein born in?", "answer": "1879", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af14", "question": "What caused the Tacoma Narrows Bridge to collapse in 1940?", "answer": "Wind (poor design and engineering led to this)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9d9", "question": "What colour is the Ring of Death that signifies that your Xbox 360 is broken forever?", "answer": "Red", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339abf", "question": "\"The Imperial March\" is the theme music of what movie villain?", "answer": "Darth Vader", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe528ec1bf59ab7d2e380ff", "question": "What classic school pet is considered a delicacy in Peru?", "answer": "Guinea pig", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c724", "question": "In North America, moss typically grows heavier on the side of trees facing which direction?", "answer": "North", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5a9e92ff7ccba3ffe45786c0", "question": "Flora Poste is the main protagonist in which novel?", "answer": "Cold Comfort Farm", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59008f18cf842fa4c4ba96b8", "question": "What did William H. Seward buy from Russia in 1867?", "answer": "Alaska", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339429", "question": "Who is \"The Jerk\"?", "answer": "Steve Martin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5febb89d7e83c707845b2134", "question": "Who said, \"History will be kind to me for I intend to write it\"?", "answer": "Winston Churchill", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59008f4fcf842fa4c4ba96ba", "question": "Who released the 1970 album \"After the Gold Rush\"?", "answer": "Neil Young", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58c8a60690aac110e4167079", "question": "What year did the Boston Tea Party take place?", "answer": "1773", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b088", "question": "What year was the Hubble telescope launched into orbit?", "answer": "1990", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58ab1c1fbaab681b0929219e", "question": "What car did Chevrolet design the Camaro to compete with in 1966?", "answer": "The Ford Mustang", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ad7ea8cb24f84e0b9f9ffd6", "question": "What is the fear of fog called?", "answer": "Homichlophobia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fefa8bc6ce05a3942286ed6", "question": "Who played the part of Max Cady in the 1962 thriller \"Cape Fear\"?", "answer": "Robert Mitchum", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5e5", "question": "Who founded eBay in 1995?", "answer": "Pierre Omidyar", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe9f4bdff048f679a45aaca", "question": "Lilapsophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Tornadoes and hurricanes", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59ae958a574a5ce6b56b8256", "question": "What is the name of the raven in George Orwell's \"Animal Farm\"?", "answer": "Moses", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58d06c40870e6f05ba600852", "question": "What character did Drew Barrymore play in the 1995 film \"Boys on the Side\"?", "answer": "Holly Pulchik", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fec88b4ec223966ae8f8822", "question": "The peripheral device that could be used to connect two Gameboys was called what?", "answer": "Game Link Cable", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339aae", "question": "What famous performer\u2019s real name was William Claude Dunkenfield?", "answer": "W.C. Fields", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58dba51e874c93a3298b214c", "question": "What country is credited with inventing the modern, self-igniting match?", "answer": "France", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d6b", "question": "Who played the role of TV's C. J. Barnes?", "answer": "David Spade", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a523", "question": "What is the capital of Lithuania?", "answer": "Vilnius", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5da855951aec824685d88d02", "question": "What team was \"plagued\" by the \"Curse of the Bambino\"?", "answer": "The Boston Red Sox", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9a3", "question": "Ascorbic acid is commonly referred to as what?", "answer": "Vitamin C", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5bfdffddb668d7dfe168b5bc", "question": "Chablis wine comes from which French wine region?", "answer": "Burgundy", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea4653ff048f679a45aba1", "question": "What kind of muscle contraction is also referred to as \"static tension\"?", "answer": "Isometric", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ad7ea81b24f84e0b9f9ffd5", "question": "Homichlophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Fog or humidity", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ab1b3ef4fda37788a9a1dc5", "question": "Where is the Salvador Dali museum located?", "answer": "St. Petersburg, Florida", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fd6a1826c0f9723ab15cb3a", "question": "Who was the first honorary citizen of the U.S.?", "answer": "Winston Churchill", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5f164c83f9b80650dbe7f92f", "question": "Who plays Thor in the 2017 film \"Thor: Ragnarok\"?", "answer": "Chris Hemsworth", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5de65a4cf89b9ec3da2d335e", "question": "Who played Bruce Wayne in the 1989 film \"Batman\"?", "answer": "Michael Keaton", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fc8559fabc30a8194e188ae", "question": "Who starred in both of the films \"Jaws\" and \"The Deep\"?", "answer": "Robert Shaw", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd6a70d6c0f9723ab15cb5a", "question": "What is the crescent-shaped part of a fingernail called?", "answer": "Lunula", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd6a3346c0f9723ab15cb4b", "question": "What was Ronald Reagan\u2019s Secret Service code name?", "answer": "Rawhide", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff517f2ff04d658268c92fd", "question": "Who was the \"Lady Bandit of Arizona\"?", "answer": "Pearl Hart", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe7678deec85e375820b292", "question": "Which country has the most known animal species?", "answer": "Brazil", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133987a", "question": "In Star Wars, where is Princess Leia from?", "answer": "Alderaan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388b8", "question": "In the children's toe-counting rhyme, what did the third little piggy have?", "answer": "Roast Beef", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff0b5f5e662d71a53651000", "question": "What was the most popular type of paint during the Renaissance?", "answer": "Oil", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aab1", "question": "Which bird is the national bird of the Bahamas?", "answer": "American flamingo", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be6b", "question": "What is Dodger Stadium also known as?", "answer": "Chavez Ravine", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58f167f2f7c52aae91cc07c0", "question": "What is a brickfielder?", "answer": "Hot and dry Southern Australian wind", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395ee", "question": "In The Simpsons, what is the name of the studio where Krusty's show is taped?", "answer": "Krustylu Studios", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff14380b0ee8c595b6d39b2", "question": "Who wrote the 15th century novel \"The Tale of Two Lovers\"?", "answer": "Pope Pius II", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339257", "question": "Whose mother complained about his swearing in the film \"GoodFellas\"?", "answer": "Joe Pesci's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c58", "question": "What Beatrix Potter character has siblings named Flopsy, Mopsy, and Cottontail?", "answer": "Peter Rabbit", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3a9", "question": "The composer Berlioz married Harriet Smithson in which year?", "answer": "1833", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339079", "question": "Who wrote the opera \"Turandot\"?", "answer": "Giacomo Puccini", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5ca", "question": "What bird, also known as a Man O'War, can glide for hours without flapping its wings?", "answer": "Magnificent Frigatebird", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338be4", "question": "What is the name of the controversial novel that was written by Salmon Rushdie?", "answer": "The Satanic Verses", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe8acf701dd7bf43be5e773", "question": "What was the color orange named after?", "answer": "The citrus fruit", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a27", "question": "Which great Renaissance artist designed the dome of St. Peter's Basilica in Rome?", "answer": "Michelangelo", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a617", "question": "What country's major seaport is Alexandria?", "answer": "Egypt", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c05f", "question": "What is the name of the oscar winning actor who is the spokesperson for Farmer's Insurance?", "answer": "J.K. Simmons", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0fe", "question": "The flowers of the curry tree are what color?", "answer": "White", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4e4", "question": "What does GT stand for in the automotive world?", "answer": "Grand Tourer", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a024", "question": "What is the name of the arrogant male co-anchor of Channel 5 News in the TV show \"Family Guy\"?", "answer": "Tom Tucker", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59cdb23465ff7d326b622a72", "question": "What are the primary ingredients of the dish \"Angels on Horseback\"?", "answer": "Oysters and bacon", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad93", "question": "What British Lord outlawed Christmas and, by extension, Santa, in 1647?", "answer": "Lord Oliver Cromwell", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c522", "question": "What is an uncastrated, adult male horse called?", "answer": "Stallion", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c146", "question": "How many dots are there on a die?", "answer": "21", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7af", "question": "The Latin name for copper comes from what island where the ore was mined?", "answer": "Cyprus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ce8", "question": "What breed of dog is Marmaduke in the comic strip?", "answer": "Great Dane", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339668", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", who is Radioactive Man's boy sidekick?", "answer": "Fallout Boy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e94", "question": "What Harry Potter snacks come in flavors including earwax, booger, and vomit?", "answer": "Bertie Bott's Every Flavor Beans", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59ae9503574a5ce6b56b824f", "question": "Lilongwe is the capital of which African country?", "answer": "Malawi", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b417", "question": "Who was the first person to reach the North Pole in 1909?", "answer": "Robert Peary", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5a162a64f01ec323f8491723", "question": "What carries sensations from the tongue to the brain?", "answer": "Lingual nerve", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd6a00d6c0f9723ab15cb32", "question": "What year was the first black hole discovered?", "answer": "1971", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a337", "question": "Which actress was dubbed \"The Scream Queen\" after appearing in numerous horror films?", "answer": "Jamie Lee Curtis", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe76f9eeec85e375820b2ec", "question": "The Atlantic Ocean Road links islands in what country?", "answer": "Norway", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6015e58bfe83fe1f2a824bc0", "question": "Broadway was established in what year in New York?", "answer": "1750", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa84", "question": "What is the capital of Djibouti?", "answer": "Djibouti City", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fede6496ce05a3942286dfb", "question": "Who wrote the music for the Holiday classic film \"White Christmas\"?", "answer": "Irving Berlin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4b2", "question": "Hepatitis is the inflammation of which of the body's organs?", "answer": "Liver", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5f9f4335af848b908361b870", "question": "Which is the largest city in Africa?", "answer": "Cairo", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b098", "question": "What 20th \u00adcentury conflict was dubbed the \"forgotten war\"?", "answer": "The Korean War", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b33", "question": "What 1980s movie soundtrack gave us the #1 hit by the band Berlin titled \"Take My Breath Away\"?", "answer": "Top Gun", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b870", "question": "Ashtanga, Bikram, and Kundalini are all types of what?", "answer": "Yoga", "category": "general"}, {"id": "60062b98c9d816e292245c20", "question": "Where is the first underwater art museum in the U.S.?", "answer": "Santa Rosa Beach, Florida", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c636", "question": "Which two features are longer on a hare than a rabbit?", "answer": "Legs and Ears", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58dba5c5874c93a3298b2153", "question": "\"An Inconvenient Truth\" is a 2006 documentary film directed by Davis Guggenheim about what subject?", "answer": "Global Warming", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb14", "question": "How many playing pieces does each player begin with in Backgammon?", "answer": "15", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c692", "question": "A nebula is a large interstellar cloud of what?", "answer": "Dust and gases", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339492", "question": "Who directed the 1999 movie \"The Green Mile\"?", "answer": "Frank Darabont", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0cc", "question": "What is the official name for the \"pound\" or \"number\" symbol on the telephone keypad?", "answer": "Octothorpe", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe6a7cf20565ad31a57c7ef", "question": "What was the first US state to pass a law requiring mandatory seat belt use?", "answer": "New York", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ef7", "question": "Whose sensei is a rat named Master Splinter?", "answer": "The Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59675c4d2b59efe0e9417e94", "question": "What was Vince Gill\u2019s last #1 as a solo recording artist?", "answer": "Tryin\u2019 To Get over You", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ad9e088e748bb36357acdee", "question": "Swiftcurrent Mountain is in what United States National Park?", "answer": "Glacier National Park", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ffb69d05dad637d903c884a", "question": "What US state has a diamond illustrated on its license plate?", "answer": "Arkansas", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5a9e93f47ccba3ffe45786cc", "question": "What year was Buddy Holly born?", "answer": "1936", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cf9", "question": "Captain Nemo is a character in which book?", "answer": "20,000 Leagues Under the Sea", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c789", "question": "The Earth's ozone layer absorbs what type of radiation from the Sun?", "answer": "Ultraviolet", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c890", "question": "What does the Mohs scale measure?", "answer": "Mineral hardness", "category": "science"}, {"id": "601b4b9949076251badbeac5", "question": "The Iditarod Trail Sled Dog Race was inspired in part by what event?", "answer": "A diphtheria outbreak -- In 1925, several teams of mush dogs relayed a serum for diphtheria from Seward to Nome, Alaska.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b301", "question": "In what city is the Schloss Cecilienhof, site of a historic 1945 conference?", "answer": "Potsdam", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339884", "question": "In Disney's \"Aladdin\", what is the name of Jasmine's pet tiger?", "answer": "Rajah", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b34", "question": "What famous fashion designer did Rachel begin working for in Season 5 of the TV show \"Friends\"?", "answer": "Ralph Lauren", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59f9b9f6364247bf200fb893", "question": "What is a \"Shoal\"?", "answer": "A group of fish", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe734e4eec85e375820b23e", "question": "Which of Adolf Hitler's close associates fled to Scotland?", "answer": "Rudolph Hess", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58ec26748dc25ca9e12ef64b", "question": "Which musical act went by the name \"Two Tons O' Fun\" in their early carrier?", "answer": "The Weather Girls", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffb69055dad637d903c8845", "question": "In which national capital can you find around 200,000 gers (traditional round tents) alongside other kinds of\u202fhousing?", "answer": "Ulaanbaatar, Mongolia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9c6", "question": "What disease is considered the human form of \"Mad Cow's Disease\"?", "answer": "Creutzfeldt-Jakobs Disease", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1a1", "question": "Which staircase in the Leaning Tower of Pisa has fewer steps?", "answer": "The north-facing one", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fdffc6d1cf6db9ac4808cfe", "question": "Where is the world's largest building carved out of a single rock?", "answer": "India", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133897e", "question": "Andy Warhol was born in what US city?", "answer": "Pittsburgh", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bc6", "question": "What was the name of the ship that Jason & his Argonauts sail in?", "answer": "Argo", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399a5", "question": "What Hanna-Barbera cartoon characters were patterned after Ed Norton from the TV series \"The Honeymooners\"?", "answer": "Yogi Bear and Barney Rubble", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5b69910ae762b54eb9be9416", "question": "Up until the modern times, what type of gift was usually associated with 20th wedding anniversary?", "answer": "China", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394a3", "question": "What was B.J.'s full name in the TV show \"B.J. and the Bear\"?", "answer": "Billie Joe McKay", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5b174533bb2d29f81593b6ff", "question": "What is the fear of going to bed known as?", "answer": "Clinophobia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fed2bbaec223966ae8f8911", "question": "What is the name of the smelly green ghost in \"Ghostbusters\"?", "answer": "Slimer", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b592", "question": "What does the abbreviation SUV stand for?", "answer": "Sport Utility Vehicle", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a86c", "question": "The Galapagos Islands are a province located in which country?", "answer": "Ecuador", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fea43d8ff048f679a45ab89", "question": "What is the scientific study of human movement?", "answer": "Kinesiology", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe4ec5506d333868d34d764", "question": "What is the name of the economic program that was created to help Puerto Rico?", "answer": "Operation Bootstrap", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397aa", "question": "What was the family name of circus showmen Al, Alfred, John, Otto and Charles?", "answer": "Ringling", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393ef", "question": "What actor was the executive producer of the mystery series \"Push, Nevada\"?", "answer": "Ben Affleck", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58d118c64fea7fe947a22288", "question": "How many successive Wimbledon titles did Bjorn Borg win?", "answer": "5", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133960b", "question": "Who played Captain Leo Davidson in the 2001 version of the movie \"Planet of the Apes\"?", "answer": "Mark Wahlberg", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59e3f7525cb9e8bda682136f", "question": "The wreckage of which ship was discovered in 1985?", "answer": "Titanic", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fc2f265cee580c7f8fd1e52", "question": "Who said, \"Winners never quit, and quitters never win.\"?", "answer": "Vince Lombardi", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe7c397877e98cb97778996", "question": "Where is the natural gas-burning \"Fire Mountain\" located?", "answer": "Azerbaijan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5af98753aeb0982ee4559553", "question": "What is believed to be the first political cartoon published in colonial America?", "answer": "Join or Die Cartoon", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fe8", "question": "What children's TV character lived in the Treasure House?", "answer": "Captain Kangaroo", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7c298877e98cb9777898c", "question": "Who does Queen Elizabeth need permission from to enter the City of London?", "answer": "The Lord Mayor", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5c3e988bebfabb9c85d8a96c", "question": "Which leader was renowned for his \"Blood and Iron\" speech?", "answer": "Otto von Bismarck", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c84b", "question": "In what organ of the human body would you find the malleus?", "answer": "The ear", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59ded1b3ea2747c8aff16d35", "question": "What year was the word \"motel\" first used?", "answer": "1925", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2eb", "question": "What is the largest animal to have ever existed?", "answer": "Blue whale", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba43", "question": "The military training center of Fort Sill is located in which US state?", "answer": "Oklahoma", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a658", "question": "What historic theater district is located in New York?", "answer": "Broadway", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5990afb8b72eedf883a8c70a", "question": "Where were the Pillars of Hercules located?", "answer": "Strait of Gibraltar", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59068295ff9c0647b50a809e", "question": "On what streaming platform was Kanye West\u2019s \"The Life of Pablo\" album launched?", "answer": "Tidal", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a25f2236682715b82711ce8", "question": "Feijoada, the national dish of Brazil, originates from which European country?", "answer": "Portugal", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b057", "question": "Who was Michael Dukakis\u2019s Vice-Presidential running mate in the 1988 US Presidential election?", "answer": "Lloyd Bentsen", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c167", "question": "Who is Edson Arantes do Nascimento better known as?", "answer": "Pele", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5f164eb8f9b80650dbe7f937", "question": "What color is the \"Reality stone\" in the 2017 Marvel Legacy relaunch?", "answer": "Red", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fea33deff048f679a45aaf1", "question": "Nikola Tesla started his career working for which later rival?", "answer": "Thomas Edison", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bff6", "question": "What is an eyrie?", "answer": "The nest of a bird of prey", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a023", "question": "What is the name of the female co-anchor who died in the TV show \"Family Guy\"?", "answer": "Diane Simmons", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015f1fdfe83fe1f2a824c18", "question": "What is the first of the four cups of wine diners are obligated to drink at the Passover Seder meant for?", "answer": "Kiddush", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abc8", "question": "Pretoria is the capital of which country?", "answer": "South Africa", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe8aaba01dd7bf43be5e75f", "question": "Chartreuse is a color between yellow and what?", "answer": "Green", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af20", "question": "What name is given to William the conqueror's survey of England in 1086?", "answer": "The Domesday Book", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae21", "question": "What is the famous brewery founded in Dublin in 1759?", "answer": "Guinness", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5b7ab8e46490a8cc1a6e528e", "question": "In \"The Adventures of Pinocchio\", who did Pinocchio accidentally kill?", "answer": "The Talking Cricket", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3f8", "question": "Which is the shallowest sea on Earth?", "answer": "Sea of Azov", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338880", "question": "What is the last word in the Bible?", "answer": "Amen", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fffa8a573838c5c8a417f3f", "question": "How are elements organized on the periodic table?", "answer": "By atomic number - The atomic number corresponds to the number of protons in the nucleus.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1de", "question": "Which members of the \"Bee Gees\" were twins?", "answer": "Maurice and Robin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b535", "question": "How many pawns does each player have at the start of a chess game?", "answer": "Eight", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5a9e94cc7ccba3ffe45786d7", "question": "What year did the programming language \"COBOL\" first appear, before being standardized in 1968?", "answer": "1959", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339dff", "question": "Whose tombstone bears the inscription \"That's All Folks\"?", "answer": "Mel Blanc", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fef93616ce05a3942286e8d", "question": "NFL footballs are made out of which material?", "answer": "Cowhide", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5901d8c7709c1c34536e6ea7", "question": "In what country was the first coin operated slot machine invented?", "answer": "US", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5f6", "question": "What cut of steak got its name from the New York City coach stop where it was first served?", "answer": "Porterhouse", "category": "general"}, {"id": "601b4b4f49076251badbeac2", "question": "The month of July was named after whom?", "answer": "Julius Caesar-- It was named by the Roman Senate in honor of the Roman general and statesman, it being the\u00a0month\u00a0of his birth.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acea", "question": "Which president's wife helped fund the war effort by auctioning wool from sheep grazing on the White House lawn?", "answer": "Woodrow Wilson's", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c17d", "question": "What is the opposite of an utopia?", "answer": "Dystopia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c036", "question": "What are Limerick, Round Bend, Aberdeen and Octopus?", "answer": "Fishing hooks", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e07", "question": "What 1993 movie's title character is actually out-of-work voice actor Daniel Hillard?", "answer": "Mrs. Doubtfire", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf46", "question": "What is the full moon nearest the autumnal equinox called?", "answer": "Harvest moon", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c645", "question": "What is the center of an atom called?", "answer": "Nucleus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fecc0f8ec223966ae8f8862", "question": "Why were the Boston Red Sox said to be \"cursed\" between 1918 and 2004?", "answer": "For trading Babe Ruth", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6015e63afe83fe1f2a824bc9", "question": "Who ultimately succeeded King Alfred the Great as \"King of the Anglo-Saxons\"?", "answer": "Edward the Elder", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe1f3ec145fb2946670739c", "question": "What is the main ingredient in the Scottish dish \"stovies\"?", "answer": "Potatoes", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a98f", "question": "What city named its airport after Ted Stevens?", "answer": "Anchorage", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6010c6d70775fa611bce67d3", "question": "What popular 1990s toy was banned from the U.S. National Security Agency's HQ?", "answer": "Furby -- It had a recording and repeating function. It could be a problem in a place full of confidential material.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d6d", "question": "What classic novel's subtitle is \"And What Alice Found There\"?", "answer": "Through the Looking-Glass", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae19", "question": "In which decade did Hawaii become a state?", "answer": "1950s", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133978f", "question": "What did Def Leppard drummer Rick Allen lose in a 1984 auto accident?", "answer": "An arm", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a1e1d67b5a031299b74573a", "question": "The Okapi is native to which country?", "answer": "Congo", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338928", "question": "Which rock group charted \"Land of Confusion\" in 1986?", "answer": "Genesis", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe8ab4d01dd7bf43be5e767", "question": "What part of the computer does \"QWERTY\" refer to?", "answer": "The keyboard", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a374", "question": "What is the capital of Romania?", "answer": "Bucharest", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2b1", "question": "What US president returned the US controlled Panama Canal Zone to Panama?", "answer": "Jimmy Carter", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0a5", "question": "What is the first name of Fidel Castro's brother, who became Cuba's acting president when Fidel fell ill?", "answer": "Raul", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339baf", "question": "What knighted English actor played Gandalf in \"The Lord of the Rings\" film trilogy?", "answer": "Ian McKellan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd2d7522596a59cbdfbd3b4", "question": "Who gave the famous speech, \"Give me liberty or give me death\"?", "answer": "Patrick Henry", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd2d0342596a59cbdfbd378", "question": "Who said, \"Nature has given us two ears, two eyes, and but one tongue-to the end that we should hear and see more than we speak\"?", "answer": "Socrates", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe73e11eec85e375820b270", "question": "Which country do the Shetland Islands belong to?", "answer": "United Kingdom", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7bc", "question": "What natural \"Wonder of the World\" lies off the east coast of Australia?", "answer": "The Great Barrier Reef", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a00e", "question": "Whose Atlantic recordings are collected in a set called \"Queen of Soul\"?", "answer": "Aretha Franklin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac06", "question": "What was the Republic of Nauru previously known as?", "answer": "Pleasant Island", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133999c", "question": "What 60\u2019s TV series featured the three Bradley daughters, Betty Jo, Billie Jo, and Bobbie Jo?", "answer": "Petticoat Junction", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "594d05491a1c922dd1ac64a1", "question": "Which islands were the subject of a war between Argentina and United Kingdom in the 1980s?", "answer": "Falklands", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa78", "question": "What major mountain ranges are located in New York State?", "answer": "Adirondack, Catskill, and Appalachian Mountains", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c21f", "question": "When was \"Macho Man\" Randy Savage born?", "answer": "1952", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6018bc9ed96d05b23b281659", "question": "Ken Thompson and Dennis Ritchie co-created which operating system?", "answer": "Unix", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5977432a284458f1d7854427", "question": "Albert Einstein was offered the position of prime minister of what country?", "answer": "Israel", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1c5", "question": "Who was the US Green Party's first presidential candidate?", "answer": "Ralph Nader", "category": "history"}, {"id": "600f716ea9e54d890926f6e0", "question": "In which country is the Troi-Rivieres bridge?", "answer": "Canada", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f37", "question": "In \"The Arabian Nights\", the tale of Aladdin and his lamp is actually set in what non-Arabian country?", "answer": "China", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe4ded806d333868d34d71c", "question": "Who was the first Western explorer to reach China?", "answer": "Marco Polo", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59decf2fea2747c8aff16d1b", "question": "What is sometimes referred to as Zulu time?", "answer": "Greenwich Mean Time", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a951", "question": "What is the only US state that has no letters in common with its state's capital name?", "answer": "South Dakota", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133baac", "question": "What newspaper, founded in 1801, has been well known for its gossip column called \"Page Six\"?", "answer": "New York Post", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e6e", "question": "Who painted \"Water Lilies\"?", "answer": "Claude Monet", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b042", "question": "What English king was known as the \"Lionheart\"?", "answer": "Richard (I)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133904f", "question": "Who composed \"Peter and the Wolf\"?", "answer": "Sergei Prokofiev", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b902", "question": "What color are many casinos decorated in to make patrons less aware of passing time?", "answer": "Red", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2a0", "question": "Which comedian created the character of Maude Frickert?", "answer": "Jonathan Winters", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bc3", "question": "In what year was David Bowie awarded the Grammy Lifetime Achievement Award?", "answer": "2006", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58bb338ce368446ca7bd6845", "question": "In \"The Wizard of Oz\", what was the lion looking for?", "answer": "Courage\u00a0", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5e90feced7247dfc0fa00309", "question": "In what year was \"Harry Potter and the Sorcerer's Stone\" published in the US?", "answer": "1998", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d0e", "question": "What literary character lived at 221B Baker Street?", "answer": "Sherlock Holmes", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a52", "question": "What TV family had three sons named Brad, Mark, and Randy?", "answer": "The Taylor's from Home Improvement", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb13", "question": "Often worn by young girls, \"Mary Janes\" are what type of fashion item?", "answer": "Shoes", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd2cfdc2596a59cbdfbd374", "question": "Who said, \u201cWorthless people love only to eat and drink; people of worth eat and drink only to live\"?", "answer": "Socrates", "category": "history"}, {"id": "594a64d92ebb971c1417fba9", "question": "What year did Grace Kelly appear on an US postage stamp?", "answer": "1993", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcf8", "question": "What rubber Wham-O toy inspired the name of one of the world's largest sporting events?", "answer": "The Super Bowl", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ba4", "question": "Which state is located between Wisconsin and North Dakota?", "answer": "Minnesota", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c48d", "question": "What does an ornithologist study?", "answer": "Birds", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6007820ebd51d85e222ab652", "question": "What object commonly appears in Picasso's paintings?", "answer": "Guitars (Although his Cubist works approach abstraction, he never relinquished the objects of the real world as subject matter.)", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ffb5a8c5dad637d903c8817", "question": "How many islands are in the so-called Thousand Islands area of the Saint Lawrence River?", "answer": "1,864", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b939", "question": "What is the usual age for a Jewish boy to celebrate his Bar Mitzvah?", "answer": "13", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb08", "question": "What newspaper was founded in 1889 by Charles H. Dow and Edward Jones?", "answer": "Wall Street Journal", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a4", "question": "What city is the TV show \"Sex and the City\" based in?", "answer": "New York", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a227", "question": "What year did Puff Daddy record the song \"I'll Be Missing You\"?", "answer": "1997", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a4a991561d1b4d384d5d696", "question": "How long was the TV show \"Gunsmoke\" between 1955 and 1961?", "answer": "30 minutes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398f9", "question": "What late night talk show's house band is Cleto & The Cletones?", "answer": "Jimmy Kimmel Live!", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133930f", "question": "In \"The Big Lebowski\", what did Jeffrey Lebowski want replaced after it was urinated on?", "answer": "His rug", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015e55afe83fe1f2a824bbb", "question": "The mother of the youngest Pandavas is?", "answer": "Madri", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133946b", "question": "What movie earned Katharine Hepburn her last Oscar?", "answer": "On Golden Pond", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a162cd9f01ec323f8491733", "question": "Tradionally, what does a Fletcher make?", "answer": "Arrows", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c02", "question": "What is actor Jack Nicholson's full birthname?", "answer": "John Joseph Nicholson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fec8b4eec223966ae8f883a", "question": "The movie \"Rush Hour 2\" poked humor at China for consuming which type of animal meat?", "answer": "Dog", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fecc2f4ec223966ae8f8879", "question": "Which major sports league does not let its players to wear the number 0?", "answer": "MLS", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af89", "question": "Who was the second president of the US?", "answer": "John Adams", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a006", "question": "What movie kills off a racehorse named Khartoum?", "answer": "The Godfather", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bb9", "question": "What was Jefferson's last name on the TV show \"Married with Children\"?", "answer": "D'Arcy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338dc8", "question": "Whose sidekick was named Passepartout?", "answer": "Phileas Fogg", "category": "arts"}]